翻译: Ginger 小田切KV 自心 sweump 小萌
校对: 店小二 怪查理
后期: 小萌
电波字幕组 诚心诚译
压制: 英俊君
分 歧 者
芝加哥
我们很幸运能住在这座城里
We're lucky to be in The City.
据他们说之前的战争十分可怕
They say the war was terrible.
城市以外的世界都毁灭了
That the rest of the world was destroyed.
我们的先人筑墙保障我们的安全
Our founders built the wall to keep us safe
他们把我们分成五个派系
and they divided us into five groups, factions,
维护和平
to keep the peace.
那些重视知识和逻辑的聪明人
The smart ones, the ones who value knowledge and logic
是博学派
are in Erudite.
他们无所不知
They know everything.
友好派会耕作
Amity farm the land.
他们友善和谐 一直很快乐
They're all about kindness and harmony, always happy.
诚实派看重诚信和秩序
Candor value honesty and order.
他们不管他人想法 只说实话
They tell the truth, even when you wish they wouldn't.
还有无畏派
And then there's Dauntless.
他们是我们的守护者 士兵和警察
They're our protectors, our soldiers, our police.
我一直觉得他们很棒
I always thought they were amazing.
英勇 无畏 自由自在
Brave, fearless and free.
有人觉得他们是疯子
Some people think Dauntless are crazy,
其实某种程度上确实如此
which they kind of are.
这边 Beatrice
Come on, Beatrice.
我是无私派
My faction is Abnegation.
别人管我们叫"呆瓜"
The others all call us "Stiffs."
我们生活简朴
We lead a simple life,
无私奉献 帮助他人
selfless, dedicated to helping others.
我们甚至会接济
We even feed the Factionless,
那些无法融入他人的无派者
the ones who don't fit in anywhere.
因为我们是公仆
Because we're public servants,
所以大家放心让我们管理政府
we're trusted to run the government.
我爸爸跟着我们的领袖Marcus工作
My father works alongside our leader, Marcus.
这制度运转良好 每个人都知道自己的位置
It all works. Everyone knows where they belong.
但我除外
Except for me.
我妈妈说迷失自我也是一种艺术
My mother says there's an art to losing yourself.
但我还没想通这点
But I haven't figured it out yet.
我本不应该考虑自己
I'm supposed to never think of myself,
而应该帮助他人
to always help others.
不要一直照镜子
To never look too long in the mirror.
紧张吗
Are you nervous?
不
No.
你当年会吗 为测试而紧张
Were you? For your test?
不 不
Mmm-mm. No.
我简直吓呆了
I was terrified.
其实我没必要紧张 你也一样
But I didn't have any reason to be and neither do you.
只能看到这儿了
That's all you get.
规矩就是规矩
Rules are rules.
我今天要参加测试
Today I take the test.
我很怕自己不是无私派
I'm scared it'll tell me I'm not Abnegation.
那样我就得离开我现在的家
That I have to leave my family.
但我更怕让我留在这里
But I'm even more scared that it will tell me to stay.
对于我弟弟Caleb来说 这不算什么
For my brother Caleb, it's easy.
我来帮你拿包吧
Let me help you with that.
他天生无私
He's a natural.
Beatrice 你可以帮忙拿剩下的包吗
Beatrice, do you wanna get the other bags?
不好意思
Sorry.
那如果她是盲人或者残疾人呢
What if she'd been blind or an amputee?
你就会帮她了吗
Would you have helped her then?
- 我是想着要帮她来着  - 没那么难
- I was thinking about helping her. - It's not that hard.
对你来说可能是这样
For you, maybe.
放轻松 Beatrice 深呼吸 相信测试
Just relax, Beatrice. Take a deep breath and trust the test.
相信测试
Trust the test.
测试会让我了解自身 自己的归属
Test will tell me who I am, where I belong.
我聪明吗
Am I smart?
善良吗 诚实吗
Kind? Am I honest?
无私吗 勇敢吗
Selfless? Or brave?
嘿 那些我们都得不到的食物
Hey. So, all the food that we're not getting,
你们分给那些无派者吗
you guys are giving away to the Factionless?
- 对吗  - 对啊
- Right? Yeah? - Yeah.
你在说谎 你为什么说谎
You're a liar. Why are you lying to me?
谁都知道你会中饱私囊
Everybody knows you keep it for yourselves.
你们为什么不索性承认了
So why don't you just admit it?
回答我
Huh?
我在跟你说话 你们这些呆瓜都聋了吗 听到没
I'm talking to you. Are all you stiffs deaf or somethin'? Hey!
Beatrice
Beatrice...
别冲动
Don't.
一百年前 战争刚刚结束
One hundred years ago, after the war,
城市创建者们设立了这个制度
our founders created a system
他们觉得这个系统可以预防冲突 维持长久的和平
they believed would prevent future conflict and create lasting peace.
今天 基于你们人格的能力测试
Today, aptitude testing based on your personality
将会决定你们归属的派系
will assign you to one of the factions.
尽管我们认为根据测试结果
While it is our belief that choosing the faction
选择派别
indicated by your test is the
是保持派系制度良好运转的最佳方法
best way to ensure success within the faction system,
但你们在明天的选派仪式上
it is your right tomorrow at the choosing ceremony
有权背离测试结果
to choose any of the five factions,
自由选择派系
regardless of your test results.
但一旦选择完毕
However, once the choice has been made,
派系无法更改
there will be no change permitted.
你们无私派都不喜欢照镜子吗
What is it with you Abnegation in mirrors?
我们拒绝虚荣
We reject vanity.
好吧 我知道了 坐吧
Yeah. I know. Sit down.
我是Tori 我是你的考官
I'm Tori. I'll be administering your test.
你会面临一系列的选择
You'll be offered a series of choices
来测量你各个派系的符合程度
to test your aptitude for each faction
直到得出结果
until you get one result.
不必紧张
I wouldn't sweat it.
95%的人都会待在他们原来的派系里
95% get the faction of their origin,
就你的情况来看
and from the looks of you...
这是什么
What is it?
喝光它
Bottoms up.
选吧
Choose.
快选 不然就来不及了
Now. Before it's too late.
- 为什么 我选他们干嘛  - 选一个
- Why? What will I do with them? - Choose.
告诉我吧
Just tell me.
狗狗
Puppy!
快起来
Get up.
趁主管进来之前 快从后门走
We're going out the back door before a supervisor comes.
- 那我的结果是什么  - 快走
- But what was my result? - Come on!
怎么了
What happened?
你就跟你家人说那血清让你难受
You're going to tell your family that the serum made you sick
然后我让你回家了
and that I sent you home.
- 好吗  - 不 先告诉我结果
-All right? - No, but what was my result?
无私派
Abnegation.
同时也是博学派和无畏派
And Erudite. And Dauntless.
无畏派
Dauntless...
你的测试没有确定结果
Your results were inconclusive.
不可能 这说不通啊
That's impossible. It doesn't make any sense.
不 不是不可能 只是概率极低
No. Not impossible. It's just extremely rare.
他们管这种人叫"分歧者"
They call it "Divergent."
这件事你不能跟别人说 包括你父母
You can't tell anyone about this. Not even your parents.
对外界来说
As far as the world is concerned,
你得到的结果就是无私派
you received an Abnegation result
我会手动输入这个结果
because that is what I manually entered.
那我在选派大会上怎么办
So what am I supposed to do at the choosing ceremony?
我应该知道我未来要做什么
I was supposed to learn what to do.
而这场测试就是为了告诉我应该选什么派系的
This was supposed to tell me what faction to choose, the test.
我们应该相信测试
We're supposed to trust the test.
测试对你没用
The test didn't work on you.
你要相信自己
You have to trust yourself.
你今天怎么啦
What happened to you today?
测试结束后 你去哪了
Where did you go after your test?
我不舒服 他们就把我先送回家了
I got sick, so they sent me home early.
你做完测试了吗
Did you finish your test?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
结果是什么
What was your result?
你的是什么
What was yours?
你怎么一声不吭自己走了
Why did you just leave without telling anybody?
我当时很难受
I was sick.
Beatrice...
你还没意识到我们现在所处的困境吗
I don't think you understand the level of scrutiny we're under.
他们使出一切伎俩降低我们的公信度
They're doing everything they can to discredit us right now.
谁
Who is?
博学派
Erudite.
他们觉得应该由他们管理政府 不是我们
They believe that they should be the governing faction, not us.
所以从现在开始你们要小心了
So you have to be careful right now, okay?
连Marcus也受到攻击
Even Marcus is under attack.
为什么
For what?
这是一条陈年的指控了
It's an old accusation.
说他虐待他儿子
That he mistreated his son
所以他儿子转派了
and that's why the boy defected.
- 真的吗  - 不是
- Is that true? - No.
当然不是
'Course not.
孩子们转派的原因有很多
Children defect for all kinds of reasons.
别在这待太久 早点上床好好睡一觉
Don't take too long in here. You need a good night's sleep...
明天还有大会呢
For tomorrow.
我 额
I, um...
我们爱你们
We love you.
晚安
Good night.
宝贝 我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you, honey.
- Beatrice  –怎么了
- Beatrice? - What?
明天选派的时候
Tomorrow when we choose...
你要想想你的家人
You have to think of the family.
知道
Yeah.
但你也要考虑你自己
But you also have to think of yourself.
众派系 请在规定的区域集合
Factions, please gather in your assigned areas.
早上好 Jeanine
Morning, Jeanine.
早啊 Andrew Marcus怎么样了
Good morning, Andrew. How is Marcus holding up?
他很好
As well as can be expected.
我们得揪出那些造谣者
We need to find out who's behind these rumors.
我们都清楚是谁干的
I think we all know who it is.
如果是博学派的人干的 我一定会找出元凶
If it's someone from Erudite, I promise I'll find out who.
这些你的孩子
These are your children.
我都不知道他们今天选派
I don't think I knew they were choosing today.
- 你叫什么名字  - 我 叫Caleb
- What's your name? - I'm... I'm Caleb.
- 幸会  - 我叫Jeanine Matthews
- It's a pleasure to meet you. - Jeanine Matthews.
你是
And you are?
她叫Beatrice
This is Beatrice.
你们今天可要面临重大的抉择
Well, you both have a big decision to make today.
我相信无论你们选什么 父母都会支持的
I'm sure your parents will support whatever choice you make.
应该没什么好选的吧
That's not supposed to be a choice.
测试已经告诉我们应该怎么做了
The test should tell us what to do.
- 你仍然有选择的自由啊  - 但你并不想这样
- You're still free to choose. - But you don't really want that.
Beatrice
Beatrice...
我希望你能选择做真实的自己
I want you to choose who you truly are
找到真正的归属地
and where you truly belong.
而不是一时兴起 选一个你想成为 但和你不符的角色
Not on a whim. Not because you wish you were someone you're not.
但因为只有你真的了解自己
But because you honestly know yourself.
我希望你做出明智的选择
I want you to choose wisely.
我相信你会的
And I know you will.
派系制度就像是一个生物体
The faction system is a living being
你们所有人就像是细胞
composed of cells, all of you.
让这个生物体茁壮成长的唯一方法
And the only way it can survive and thrive
就是让你们选择正确的位置
is for each of you to claim your rightful place.
未来属于那些知道自己位置的人
The future belongs to those who know where they belong.
当我们离开这里时
When we leave this room,
你们就不是依赖大人的小孩了
you will no longer be dependents
你们正式成为社会一员了
but full-fledged members of our society.
派系大于血缘
Faction before blood.
我爱你
I love you...
无论怎样
No matter what.
Jonathan Ziegler
Jonathan Ziegler.
博学派
Erudite.
Jeffrey Yates
Jeffrey Yates.
无畏派
Dauntless.
Morgan Stokes
Morgan Stokes.
友好派
Amity.
Claire Satron 诚实派
Claire Satron. Candor.
Sam Robertson 无私派
Sam Robertson. Abnegation.
Caleb Prior
Caleb Prior.
博学派
Erudite.
请保持安静
Quiet, please.
Beatrice Prior
Beatrice Prior.
无畏派
Dauntless.
欢迎加入无畏派
Welcome to Dauntless!
快点 快跑
Come on! Let's go!
来啊
Come on!
对不起
Sorry.
你做到了
You made it.
- 我是Christina  - 我叫Beatrice
- I'm Christina. - Beatrice.
是我想多了还是说他们真的想杀了我们
Is it just me or are they trying to kill us?
做好准备
Get ready!
耶
Yeah!
- 他们在跳车  - 啥
- They're jumping. - What?
如果不跳会怎样
What if you don't jump?
你觉得呢 你就就会变成无派者
What do you think? You'll be factionless.
祝你好运 Al
Good luck, Al.
喔
Whoa!
- 一起吗  - 好
- Together? - Yeah.
一 二 三
One, two, three...
好了 听好了
All right, listen up!
我是Eric 你们的领袖之一
I'm Eric. I'm one of your leaders.
你们想加入无畏派的话 就要经受这种考验
If you want to enter Dauntless, this is the way in.
如果你们没胆跳下去
And if you don't have the guts to jump,
那你们就不是无畏派
then you don't belong in Dauntless.
下面有水或者什么吗
Is there water at the bottom or something?
你们会知道的
I guess you'll find out.
或者别跳
Or not.
我们才跳了车 他们又要我们跳
We just jumped. They want us to jump again?
总要有人起个头 谁来
Someone's gotta go first. Who's it gonna be?
我
Me.
是啊 呆瓜 脱了吧
Yeah, stiff, take it off!
再穿回去吧
Put it back on!
记住今天吧 新人
Today, Initiate.
你是被推下来的吗
What, you get pushed?
不是啊
No.
你叫什么
What's your name?
我叫
It's...
很难读吗
Is that a hard one?
你可以改个新的 最好选个好名字
You can pick a new one if you want, but make it good.
之后可就没机会了
You don't get to pick again.
好吧 我叫Tris
Okay... My name's Tris.
第一个跳下来的Tris
First jumper, Tris!
欢迎加入无畏派
Welcome to Dauntless.
无畏派传人的请跟Lauren走 转派过来的跟我留下
Dauntless-born, go with Lauren, transfers stay with me.
走吧
Go.
这边
This way.
我大多数时间在情报部门工作
Most of the time I work in Intelligence,
但在培训期我就是你们的教练
but during your training, I'll be your instructor.
我叫Four
My name's Four.
是数字4的那个Four吗
Four like the number?
就是数字那个
Exactly like the number.
为什么 1到3都被别人使用了吗
What happened, one through three were taken?
你叫什么
What's your name?
Christina
Christina.
Well, Christina.
这是你在我这里学到的第一课
The first lesson you learn from me
如果你想在这里活下去
if you wanna survive here,
就把嘴闭上
is keep your mouth shut.
明白吗
Do you understand me?
明白
Yes.
很好
Good.
跟我来
Follow me.
这就是深坑
This is The Pit.
这里是无畏派的生活重心
The center of life here at Dauntless.
接下来10个星期你们就睡在这里
You're gonna be sleeping here for the next 10 weeks.
这是男寝还是女寝
Girls or boys?
一起住
Both.
- 很好  - 不错
- Nice. - That works.
喜欢这样吗 那你们肯定会喜欢这的卫生间
If you like this, you're gonna love the bathroom.
太好了
Great.
好吧
Okay...
- 不是吧  - 没别的选择吗
- Seriously? - Is there no other area?
开玩笑的吧
Are you kidding?
有家的感觉吧 诚实派
You should feel right at home, Candor.
一切都坦荡荡
Everything out in the open.
开玩笑吗
Is this a joke?
换衣服
Get changed.
好吧
Right.
有人要洗澡吗
Shower, anyone?
美腿啊 呆瓜
Nice legs, stiff.
- 嘿  - 你好吗
- Hey. - How you doin'?
我们要坐这里吗
Shall we sit there?
你以前没见过汉堡吗
Have you never seen a hamburger before?
我见过 但我没吃过
No, I've seen one. I just have never eaten one.
无私派只吃粗茶淡饭
Abnegation eat plain food.
没有酱料 加一丁点调味的素菜
Plant-based diet with no sauces and a minimum of seasoning.
你刚吞的是什么书啊
Which textbook did you swallow?
我也很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you, too.
我是Will 博学派
I'm Will. Erudite.
难怪
Of course you are.
没有恶意 但无私派居然还吃饭
No offense, but I'm surprised Abnegation even eats at all.
太自私了 对吧
Too selfish, right?
难怪你会离开
No wonder you left.
要跟诚实派做朋友 你得要自信点
You gotta be pretty self-confident to be friends with a Candor.
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
你们说话不经大脑
You have no filter.
想到什么就说什么
You say the first thing that comes into your head.
例如是 你是白痴吗
You mean like, "You're an idiot"?
说得好 Al 至少我们说的是真话
Nice one, Al. At least we tell the truth.
博学派会根据事实说真话
Erudite can tell the truth because we have the facts.
我不想再听你们说旧派系的事
I don't want to hear about your old factions.
你们现在是无畏派
You're Dauntless now.
你也是转派的吗 还是无畏派传人
Were you a transfer, too? Or Dauntless-born?
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding?
没有
No.
你凭什么觉得你能跟我对话
What makes you think you can talk to me?
这
It...
肯定是因为你平易近人
Must be because you're so approachable.
小心点
Careful.
Four
Four...
我的朋友 你有这么想死吗
You, my friend, have a death wish.
知道吗 他是他班上第一
You know, he was first in his class.
他们两次想拉他进领导组 但他拒绝了
They tried to recruit him for leadership twice, but he said no.
新生 起立
Initiates, stand.
你们选择了战士派系
You have chosen to join the warrior faction
选择了保卫这个城市及其居民的安定
tasked with the defense of this city and all its inhabitants.
我们信仰着勇敢的行径
We believe in ordinary acts of bravery
还有那让我们互相支持的
and the courage that drives one person
强大勇气
to stand up for another.
谨记这信仰
Respect that.
成就我们的骄傲
Do us proud.
哇喔
Whoa!
两分钟后 全体到深坑集合
I want everyone in The Pit. Two minutes.
训练分为两个阶段
There are two stages of training.
第一个是体能阶段
The first is physical.
把自己的身体逼到极限
Push your bodies to the breaking point
掌握格斗的方法
and you'll master the methods of combat.
第二阶段就是心理训练
The second is mental.
也是 要逼到极限
Again, breaking point.
你会面对自己最恐惧的东西
You'll face your worst fears
你要征服他们 而不是被征服
and conquer them unless they get you first.
你们会跟无畏派传人分开训练
You'll be trained separately from the Dauntless-born,
但你们的排名会放在一起
but you'll be ranked together.
启蒙指导之后
After initiations,
排名结果决定你们未来的工作
rankings will determine what jobs you move into.
领导组 围墙守卫
Leadership, guarding the fence,
或是阻止无派者互相残杀
or keeping the Factionless from killing each other.
排名还决定了谁会被砍掉
The rankings will also determine who gets cut.
砍掉
Cut?
每个受训阶段结束后
At the end of each stage of training,
排名最低的新生会离开我们
the lowest-ranking Initiates will be leaving us.
去干什么
To do what?
你们肯定不能回家了
There's no going home to your families,
所以你们会成为无派者
so you'd live factionless.
- 之前怎么没说  - 这是个新规定
- Why didn't we know that? - It's a new rule.
新规定 这该事先说明啊
A new rule? Somebody should have told us that.
为什么 你会选择别的派系吗
Why? Would you have chosen differently?
出于恐惧吗
Out of fear?
要是这样的话 你现在就可以走了
I mean, if that's the case, you might as well get out now.
如果你真是无畏派的一员
If you're really one of us,
你不会在乎失败
it won't matter to you that you might fail.
既然你选择了我们
Now you chose us.
现在就轮到我们选择你了
Now we get to choose you.
从数据来看
Statistically speaking,
目前 你起码应该射中目标一次
you should have hit the target at least once by now.
哪怕只是碰巧打中
Even by accident.
发现什么了
Hey. What have you got?
无派者 无所事事
Factionless. Not doing anything.
看看 呆瓜 那是你未来的家
Check it out, stiff. That's gonna be your new family.
去打个招呼呗
Go say "Hi."
准备好上格斗场了吗
You ready for some real fighting?
差得远了
Not even close.
第一个跳的人
First jumper!
进场比赛
In the ring.
最后一个跳的人
Last jumper!
格斗时间
Time to fight.
我们要打多久
How long do we fight for?
直到其中有人不能继续为止
Till one of you can't continue.
或者有人投降
Or one of you concedes.
那是旧规定
According to the old rules.
新规定 不允许投降
New rules, no one concedes.
你真想第一场比试就闹出人命吗
You really want to lose 'em on their first fight?
勇士永不投降
A brave man never surrenders.
真幸运 我们那时还没这规定
Lucky for you, those weren't the rules when we fought.
这是算成绩的 所以全力出击吧
You'll be scored on this, so fight hard.
开始
Go!
别害怕 呆瓜
Don't be scared, stiff!
好 Tris
Nice, Tris!
- 不错  - 上
- Nice. - Yeah!
好了 大家 到这来
All right, guys, over here.
听着
Listen up.
知道这板子上的是什么吗
Know what this board is?
是你的命运
It's your life.
我们每天都给你们评分
We grade you every day.
如果你们还是在红线下
If you're still in the red
那第一阶段结束后 你们就出局了
by the end of the first stage, you're out.
我不可能做到的
I'm never gonna make it.
你可以的
Yes, you are.
我是这里最弱的
I'm the weakest one here.
那你的进步会是最大的
Then you'll be most improved.
你是诚实派的 你不该说谎
You're Candor. You're not supposed to lie.
我曾是诚实派 而且我没有说谎
I was Candor. And I'm not lying.
要是我被砍掉 我父母会让我回去的
If they cut me, I think my parents would take me back.
不 不会这样的
No, it doesn't work like that.
就算他们想这么做 但派系不会允许
Even if they wanted to, their faction wouldn't allow it.
即使我父母愿意让我回去
Even if my parents would take me back,
我也不再属于那里了
I wouldn't belong there anymore.
- 气氛有点压抑啊  - 对
- This is getting depressing. - Yeah.
你知道我们该怎么做吗
You know what we should do?
去刺青
Get tattoos.
知道吗 他们能给你脸做刺青
Did you know they had a tattoo of your face?
- 喜欢这个吗  - 喜欢
- Like it? - Yeah.
- 你要刺在哪  - 不知道
- Where would you get it? - I don't know.
你有什么建议吗
Where do you suggest?
想刺哪就刺哪
Anywhere you want.
这里 就这个吧
Here, it's this thing here.
你记得我 对吧
You remember me, right?
- 我在想你能不能  - 不能
- I was just wondering if you could... - No.
我只帮忙刺青
I just do tattoos.
好吧
Okay.
我想要这个
I'd like this one.
麻烦了
Please.
我能不能问你
Can I just ask you...
你不该选择无畏派
You made a mistake choosing Dauntless.
- 他们会查出你的  - 谁
- They'll find out about you... - Who?
他们是谁
Who will?
你威胁到的那些人
The people you're a threat to.
- 什么人 无畏派吗  - 不 是这个社会
- What people? Who, Dauntless? - No, society.
如果你不能融入一个派别 他们就控制不了你
If you don't fit into a category, they can't control you.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我是无畏派 我会成为无畏派
I'm Dauntless. I'm going to be Dauntless.
我选择了无畏派
I chose Dauntless.
希望真的是这样吧
For your sake, I hope so.
你很弱 你没有肌肉
You're weak. You have no muscle.
你这样 永远不可能赢的
You're never gonna win, not like that.
谢谢你告诉我
That's good to know.
是的 你得利用你整个身体
Yeah, you're gonna have to use your whole body.
这里绷紧
Keep tension here.
- 好的  - 然后攻击
- Okay... - And go on offense.
你很敏捷 要是你先攻击也许能赢
You're fast, so you could win if you attack first.
先靠近对手 然后猛击喉咙
You get inside, you jab to the throat.
Four
Four!
继续练吧
Keep working.
对不起 Will
Sorry about that, Will.
加油 Chris
Come on, Chris.
停 停
Stop... Stop!
我不行了 不行了
I'm done. I'm done.
你要停吗
You need to stop?
好
Okay.
我来帮你吧
Let me give you a hand.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了 大家休息一下
All right, let's everyone take a break!
你感觉好一点了吗
You feelin' a little better?
恩 好多了
Yeah, I'm fine.
哇哦
Whoa!
抓住铁轨
Grab the rail.
也可以放开
Or don't.
你有三个选择
You've got three options.
坚持着悬在半空 证明你不懦弱
Hang there and I'll forget your cowardice.
掉下去摔死
Fall and die.
或者放弃
Or give up.
但如果你放弃 你就出局了
But if you give up, you're out.
加油 Chris
Come on, Chris!
时间到
Time!
无畏派从不放弃
Dauntless never give up.
作为无畏派
As Dauntless,
我们为了围墙里每一个生命而战斗 不能失败
we fight to protect every life inside the fence, without fail.
所以我们用我们的方式来训练你们
That's why we train you the way we do.
教会你们不要放弃
To teach you not to give up.
找到具备这些能力的人
And to find out who has what it takes.
虽然外面多年来都风平浪静
Even though it's been quiet out there for years,
但随时都可能会发生变化
that could change at any moment.
所以我们得时刻准备着
So we have to be ready for everything.
喔哦
Whoo!
外面有什么
What's out there?
怪物
Monsters.
友好派的农场
Amity farms.
不 我知道这个 但再外面一点呢
No, I know. But beyond that?
战争留下的废墟
Places that never recovered from the war.
你知道吗
Do you know?
只能说 围墙的存在不是没有原因的
Let's just say they built their fence for a reason.
不是吧
Man!
你挺擅长这个啊
You're kinda good at this.
快
Come on.
还真糟糕啊
That was pathetic.
它滑出去了
It slipped.
那去捡啊
Well, go get it!
什么 他们还在扔啊
What, while they're throwing?
你怕了吗
Are you afraid?
怕被飞刀砸中吗 当然怕啊
Of getting stabbed by an airborne knife? Yeah.
全体停下
Everybody stop.
站到目标前面去
Stand in front of the target.
Four 帮我个忙
Four, gimme a hand here.
他扔飞刀的时候 你给我站在那
You're gonna stand there while he throws those knives.
要是我看到你退缩了 你就出局
And if I see you flinch, you're out.
你在这里会学到一件事
One thing you will learn here
那就是命令没的选
is that orders are not optional.
住手
Stop.
谁都能站到目标前 这证明不了什么
Anyone can stand in front of a target. It doesn't prove anything.
那么你去替代他的位置也没什么吧
Then it should be easy for you to take his place.
规则不变
Same rules apply.
别这样 Four
Oh, come on, Four.
你可以扔得更近的
You can get closer than that.
你想我给她修剪一下吗
You want me to give her a little trim?
对 离脑袋再近点
Yeah, maybe just a little off the top.
为你的勇气加分啊 呆瓜
Points for bravery, stiff.
但抵不上你顶嘴所扣的分
Not as many as you just lost for opening your mouth.
现在 小心点
Now watch yourself.
我们训练的是士兵 不是叛徒
We train soldiers, not rebels.
但今天的训练到此结束 走吧
But we're done for today. Get out.
- 你没事吧  - 你划伤我了
- You all right? - You cut me.
我故意的
I meant to.
你故意的吗
You meant to?
你以为他会让你毫发无损的离开吗
You think he was gonna let you off without a scratch?
要是我没伤到你 你现在还站在那呢
You'd still be standing there if I hadn't hit you.
所以我该向你道谢吗
So am I supposed to thank you?
你该聪明点
You're supposed to be smart.
要是我要伤害你 我早就下手了
If I wanted to hurt you, I would have.
她来了
There she is.
你真的是想死啊
You do have a death wish.
不敢相信你敢那样跟Eric说话
I can't believe you said that to Eric.
你是唯一一个敢跟他对抗的
You're the only one who's ever stood up to him.
看看你耳朵 来处理一下吧
Look at your ear. Let's get you cleaned up.
嘿 Tris 挺酷的
Hey, Tris. That was cool.
谢谢
Thanks.
太厉害了 呆瓜 恭喜
Impressive, stiff. Congrats.
闭嘴
Shut up.
怎么啦 你现在出名了
What? Hey, you're famous now.
不是因为Eric那事
I mean, not because of the thing with Eric.
你上新闻了 真的 听着
You're in the news. Yeah, listen.
最近的转派者Beatrice和Caleb Prior
"The recent transfers of Beatrice and Caleb Prior,
都是Andrew Prior的孩子
"Children of Andrew Prior, call into question the soundness
引起了人们对无私派教育和价值的质疑
"Of Abnegation's teachings and values.
是什么令他们离开呢
"What prompted them to leave?
可能答案在于
"Perhaps the answer lies
整个派系中所坚持的变质理想
in the corrupted ideal of an entire faction.
盗窃资源 整体无能
"The theft of resources, the general incompetence,
虐待孩子
"The abuse of their children."
他们打你了吗 像Marcus对他孩子那样
Did they beat you, like Marcus Eaton's kid?
他们不打任何人 他们都是好人
They didn't beat anyone. They're good people.
好吧 所以你才要离开吗
Right. And that's why you left?
我说错什么了吗
Was it something I said?
- 他是个白痴  - 对
- He's an idiot. - Yeah.
是啊 没什么
Yeah. That's okay.
她在无畏派干什么
What's she doing at Dauntless?
Prior
Prior.
你是Andrew Prior的女儿 对吧
You're Andrew Prior's daughter, aren't you?
Beatrice
Beatrice.
现在是Tris了
It's just Tris now.
Tris 我喜欢这名字
Tris, I like that.
嗯
Hmm.
你做了很好的选择 Tris
You made an impressive choice, Tris,
不在乎父母的想法和测试结果
despite your parents and your test result.
你看了我的测试结果吗
You've seen my test result?
当然了
Of course.
我很高兴你能了解自己的内心
I am glad you are smart enough to know your own mind
有什么要帮忙的就找我
Let me know if you ever need anything.
奇了怪了
Well, that was weird.
是啊
Yeah.
这是什么情况
What do you think is goin' on?
他们肯定在追捕分歧者们
I bet they're hunting Divergents.
在博学派他们就老说这事
That's all they talk about at Erudite these days.
等下 真的有分歧者吗
Wait. Divergents are real?
快跟上 Al
Come on, Al.
第一场格斗 Peter对Tris
First fight. Peter versus Tris.
什么
What?
大事不妙
Uh-oh.
肯定是Eric的主意
It's Eric.
他是在报复你
He's just trying to get back at you.
- 嘿  - 干嘛
- Hey. - What?
记得我教你的攻击方法吗
Remember what I said about attack?
先发制人 攻击咽喉
First shot, right to the throat.
好好观察他
And you watch him.
他先动脚才出拳
He steps before he punches.
记住没
All right?
嗯
Mmm.
还好吗 呆瓜
All right there, stiff?
一副要哭的样子
Look like you're about to cry.
你要真哭的话我下手会轻点
Might take it easy on you if you cry.
加油 Tris
Come on, Tris.
起来 起来
Get up. Get up.
动点真格的 别糊弄事
Come on. Stop playin' with each other.
你的气色
Wow. You look...
真差
Look bad.
我躺了多久了
How long have I been here?
差不多一天吧
About a day.
一整天吗
A day?
你们看计分表了吗 我排多少了
Have you seen the scoreboard? Where am I?
你在合格线以下
You got below the line.
你们穿这马甲是要干什么
Why are you wearing those vests?
作战演习
War games.
你起来做什么
Whoa. What are you doing?
- 我也要去  - 你不能去
- I'm coming. - You can't.
Eric说你没戏了
Eric says you're done.
什么
What?
他说你出局了
He said you're out.
Tris 你爸爸在议会工作
Your father's on the council, Tris.
或许能通融通融放你回家
Maybe they'll make an exception and let you go home.
很遗憾 Tris
We're sorry, Tris.
我们得走了 火车快开了
We gotta go. We're gonna miss the train.
好的
Yeah, okay.
- 再见  - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
多谢
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨  - 你来干什么
- Hi. - What are you doing here?
我就觉得我必须来
I just figured that I had to make it.
谁放你出来的
Who let you out?
我自己
I did.
你自己
You did?
那好
Okay.
找个位子坐下
Let's sit you down.
演习很简单 就跟抢旗子一样
The game's simple. It's like Capture the Flag.
选好武器
Weapon of choice.
就这也叫枪
You call that a gun?
神经刺弹
Neuro-stim dart.
能模拟真实枪伤的痛感
Simulates the pain of a real gunshot wound.
只有几分钟的效力
Only lasts a couple minutes.
分成两队 Four和我分别是队长
Two teams. Four and I are captains.
你先挑
You pick first.
好 Edawrd
Okay. Edward.
我选呆瓜
I'll take the stiff.
选了只小弱鸡
Oh. Picking the weak ones
这样输了也有得推脱了
so you've got someone to blame when you lose.
可以这么说吧
Something like that.
Eric队的人去哪了
Where did Eric's team go?
他们肯定在另一边
They must have gone to the end.
听好了 关掉灯光
All right. Lights off.
都围过来 快点
Gather around. Come on.
你们什么想法
Okay. What's your strategy?
我们把旗子藏好他们发现不了就行了
We can hide the flag well enough so they can't find it.
派出小分队 搜索他们的位置
Let's send out a team to scout their location.
看看能不能找到他们的旗子
See if we can find their flag.
我认为应该突袭他们
I say we blitz them. Just...
那样很快就会输的
Yeah, that's the best way to lose quickly.
我们把他们引过来
Let's make them come to us.
速战速决 他们肯定想不到
End this quickly, they won't expect it.
但我们不知道他们在哪
We don't know where they are.
我们分成两组 进攻和防御
Okay, we split into two groups, defense and offense.
- 你凭什么发号施令  - 总得有人做决定吧
- Who put you in charge? - Someone has to make a decision.
- 我们要主动出击  - 我们要谨慎行事
- We need to be more aggressive. - We need to be smart about it.
你不是要跳楼吧
You're not gonna jump, are you?
不 我只想找个有利地形
No, I'm just trying to get a good vantage point.
好主意
Good thinking.
你不用跟着我
You don't have to come with me.
你被打晕刚醒 慢着点
You should go easy. You took a beating.
你居然还知道
I'm surprised you noticed.
打到一半你不是走了吗
I saw you leave during the fight.
你们打得 我有点看不下去
Yeah, well, it's not something I wanted to watch.
嘿
Hey!
没事吧
You good?
还好吗
You okay?
没事 别担心
Yeah. I'm fine.
这里够高了
This is high enough.
不行 还要再高点
No, we need to go higher.
你没事吧
You all right?
你恐高
You're afraid of heights.
谁都有点恐惧的东西
Everyone's afraid of something.
我以为你什么都不怕呢
I didn't think you were afraid of anything.
够了吧 Tris
Come on, Tris.
开什么玩笑
Really?
你是人类吗
Are you even human?
也没那么吓人吧
This isn't so bad.
视野真好
Good eye.
你看
Look!
他们在那
There it is.
- 好 你有什么计划  - 我们分成两组
- All right. What's your plan? - We split into two groups.
我们从这边进去 其它人去和Eric交战
We'll go up this side and let the rest of you engage Eric.
- 我看见他们了  - 快走
- I can see 'em. - Go! Go!
照亮那边
Light 'em up!
还有两个人 我要再靠近了
There's two more! I'm gonna move in closer!
跟我来 走
Follow me. Go!
- 看好右边  - 快走
- Watch on your right! - Go, go, go.
走
Go.
Christina 我们走
Christina, let's go!
抓住他们
Get 'em, get 'em!
这边
This way!
- 掩护我  - 好的
- Cover me! - All right.
疼了你就告诉我
Tell me if this hurts.
还是你告诉我吧
You tell me.
你个贱人
You bitch!
混蛋
Asshole.
刚才那一枪太棒了
That was awesome!
做好隐蔽
Get covered!
上 Tris 我来望风
Go, Tris! I'll guard.
喔
Whoo!
演习结束
Game over!
Tris 干得好
Good job, Tris!
嘿 Tris
Hey, Tris!
什么事
Yeah?
跟我们走
Come with us.
你们要去哪
Where you going?
抄近路回去
Shortcut back.
无畏派特色的入派仪式
A little initiation ritual, Dauntless style.
哇
Wow.
好了 来吧
All right, let's do this!
- 好的  - 准备好了吗
- Good. - All right, you good?
- 抓紧了  - 好 走
- Hang tight. - Yeah. Go, go!
- 飞吧 亲爱的  - 呜嗷
- Fly, baby. - Whoo!
该你了
You're up.
好了 上吧
All right, do it!
加油 姑娘
Come on, girl.
去吧 Tris
Go for it! Do it, Tris!
飞过去
Like flying!
快到下面了记得刹车
Don't forget to pull the brake at the bottom!
好的
Okay.
去吧
Go.
准备好了吗
You ready?
安全带没问题
Harness is good.
刹车 拉刹车
Pull the brake! Pull the brake!
耶
Yeah!
Tris
Tris!
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
多谢
Thanks.
我想说 你今晚做得很出色
You know, I wanted to say that you were really good tonight.
很勇敢
You were brave.
嗯
Yeah.
和朋友玩去吧
Anyway, you should get back to your friends.
知道了
Okay.
你要是在合格线之上
If you're ranked above the red line,
就有资格进入第二级的训练
you'll move on to the second stage of training.
要是在合格线之下
If you're below it,
我们就不再在你身上浪费时间了
we'll waste no more time on you.
这就是你们的排名
Here are your rankings.
干得好
Nice.
你成功了
You made it.
你做到了 Tris
You made it, Tris.
- 拿到了  - 多谢
- Got it. - Thank you.
拿着
Here you go.
这就是我们通过第一阶段训练的奖励
So we pass the first stage of training, and this is our reward.
扔上来
Toss it up!
受宠若惊
Glamorous.
妈
Mom?
女儿
Oh, my girl!
妈 你来这里干什么
Mom, what are you doing here?
我就知道他们早晚
I knew they'd assign you here...
会把你分配到这里 瞧瞧你
sooner or later. Look at you!
你现在又结实又漂亮了
God, you're so strong and beautiful.
- 妈 你不该在这里  - 我知道 但你现在很危险
- Mom, you can't be here. - I know, but you're in danger.
什么
What?
我必须问问你
I had to ask you something.
你做性格测试那天没生病 对不对
You weren't sick the day you took your aptitude test, were you?
- 怎么了  - 你的测试结果是什么
- Why? - What were your test results?
亲爱的 别担心 告诉我没事
Honey, it's okay. You can tell me.
结果是 不确定
They were... They were inconclusive.
分歧者
Divergent?
千万别跟别人说
You can't tell anyone.
朋友也不行 跟教练也不能说
You can't tell your friends, your instructors.
谁都不能信
You can't trust anyone.
我不是
I'm not.
人们一直在畏惧分歧者的存在
People have always been so threatened by Divergents.
但最近博学派在到处找他们
But now Erudite is looking for them everywhere.
- 他们在搜寻他们  - 为什么
- They're actively seeking them out. - Why?
- 妈 我是什么  - 你们与他人不相容
- Mom, what am I? - You don't conform.
你们的思维千变万化
Your mind works in a
他们为此感到害怕
million different ways. They're scared of you.
第二阶段训练对你来说最危险
Stage two of training is where you are most at risk.
他们将进入你的大脑
They're gonna get inside
观察你如何应对恐惧
your head and watch how you respond to fear.
但是你可以蒙混过去
But you can pass. You can
你要装成无畏派 有人这么干过
make it through Dauntless. I have seen it before.
你怎么知道这么多有关无畏派的事
How do you know so much about this? About Dauntless?
不用管我 别让他们发现你的身份
Never mind about me. Do not let them know who you are.
慢着 你以前难道是无畏派的吗
Wait! Wait! Were you Dauntless?
- 听好了  - 嘿
- Listen. - Hey!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
车已经装好了 走吧
Truck's loaded. Let's go.
他们把她怎么了
What did they do to her?
Tris
Tris.
请坐
Take a seat.
我一会要给你注射的血清
I'm going to inject you with a serum that stimulates
会刺激大脑处理恐惧感的部分
the part of your brain that processes fear.
好的
Great.
它会让你产生幻觉
It induces a hallucination,
血清里的传送器
and then transmitters in the
能让我看到你脑海里的景象
serum allow me to see the images in your mind.
- 你能看到我的思想  - 嗯
- You can see inside my mind? - Mmm-hmm.
躺好了
Lay back.
现在 你将要面对你最恐惧的东西 Tris
Now, you're gonna be facing your worst fears, Tris.
大部分人有10到15种最怕的东西
Most people have 10 to 15 really bad ones.
你要镇定下来
You have to calm yourself.
舒缓你的心跳和呼吸
Slow your heart rate and your breathing,
专注于面前的东西
and deal with what's in front of you.
勇敢点
Be brave.
这不是真的
This isn't real.
没事了 没事了
It's all right, it's all right.
你还好吗
You okay?
你觉得你在幻觉里坚持了多久 Tris
How long do you think you were in the hallucination, Tris?
- 有20分钟吗  - 3分钟
- Twenty minutes? - Three.
比一般人快了四倍
Four times faster than the average.
我第一次见到 有人能做的这么出色
I've never seen anyone do that well the first time.
你是怎么摆脱那些鸟的
How did you get rid of the birds?
图像不太清晰
The image wasn't clear.
呃
Um...
我躲进了水里
I just went into the water.
下次就会轻松点了
Well, next time it'll be a lot easier.
还有下次吗
I have to do that again?
当然 在结束之前要联系很多次的
Yeah, you have to practice several times before the final,
但是你很有天分
but you're a natural.
没什么好担心的
You got nothing to worry about.
我全身都被小虫子覆盖了
My whole body was covered in these little insects.
眼睛里 喉咙里全是
They were in my ears, and my throat...
简直无法呼吸
I couldn't breathe.
我听说 两年前有个男的
Yeah, I heard about this guy, like two years ago...
他吓得坐在椅子上
So panicked he had a heart
突发心脏病 差点就死了
attack in his chair and he almost died.
什么
What?
我们很期待发生这种事 对不对
Yeah, so we've got that to look forward to, right?
你好像一点事都没有的样子
You didn't seem to have any problem at all.
我吗 才怪 很可怕的
Me? No, no, my God, it was awful.
别谦虚了 你坚持的时间遥遥领先
Oh, come on. No one even
你可真牛
came close to your time. You were amazing.
是啊 更棒的是
Yeah, what's amazing is that
她就要把你挤出无畏派了
she's gonna knock you right out of Dauntless.
她才不会把我挤出无畏派呢
She's not gonna knock me out of Dauntless.
她从倒数一跃成为尖子生
Look, she's gone from being the worst to one of the best.
总得有人代替她的位子吧
Somebody's gotta take her place at the bottom.
你猜会是谁 是你
Who's it gonna be? You.
你就不能闭嘴么
Do you ever stop talking?
我只想知道她是怎么做到的
I just want to know how she does it.
你耍了什么手段
What's your trick?
我没有
I don't have a trick.
没人能进步那么快的
Nobody gets through it that fast.
你还是坦白了吧
Why don't you tell us how you do it?
起码告诉你朋友们啊
At least tell your friends.
他在说什么
What's he talkin' about?
- 这个有窍门吗  - 没有
- Is there some way to make it easier? - No.
不 我什么都没干
No, I... I'm not doing anything.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
这不是真的
This isn't real.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do that?
什么
What?
你怎么打碎玻璃的
How'd you break the glass?
不知道 就那样打碎了
I don't know. Just did it.
就这么打碎了吗
You just did it?
你的测试结果是什么
What were your test results?
你的个性测试
Your aptitude test.
无私派
Abnegation.
我觉得不对
I don't think so.
什么
What?
你在撒谎
I think you're lying to me.
我为什么要撒谎
Why would I lie to you?
我再问你一次
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
你的测试结果是什么
What were your test results?
无私派
Abnegation.
你可以走了
Time for you to go.
Tris
Tris?
我要告诉你
Just so you know,
无畏派不会那样打碎玻璃的
Dauntless don't break the glass like that.
我哥和你一样
My brother was like you.
在第二阶段成绩突飞猛进
During the second stage, he got good really fast.
模拟测试的最后一天
Last day of the simulations,
无畏派的一位头头去看他
one of the Dauntless leaders came to watch him.
第二天早上
Then the next morning,
我们在深坑底发现了他的尸体
we found his body at the bottom of the chasm.
他们除掉了他
They got rid of him.
谁干的
Who did?
无畏派的头目们
Dauntless leadership.
不能让他们发现你的秘密
You can't let them find out about you.
如果他们已经知道了呢
And what if they already know?
那你现在就已经是死人了
Then you're already dead.
Beatrice
Beatrice.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我有麻烦了
I'm in trouble.
发生了什么
What happened?
我在无畏派待不下去了
I'm not gonna make it at Dauntless.
那儿不适合我
I don't fit in there.
你必须让自己适应
You have to fit in there.
我做不到
I can't.
我就是 和他们不一样
I'm just... I'm not like them.
谁会和他们一样呢 他们都是疯子
I mean, who is? They're crazy.
也许我该回到无私派
Maybe I can go back to Abnegation.
- 你回不去了  - 我知道 但是
- You can't go back. - I know, but...
他们不会让你这么做的
They're never gonna let you do that.
- 谁  - 博学派
- Who? - Erudite.
他们不会再让无私派破坏秩序了
They're not gonna let Abnegation break any more rules.
他们真以为现在是他们执政了吗
They actually think that they're running the government now?
可能真快了
They might be soon.
等等 你说真的
Wait. Really?
博学派应该执政 而不是无私派
Erudite should be in charge. Certainly not Abnegation.
等等 Caleb 你怎么能这么说
Wait, hold on, Caleb. How can you say that?
这也是其他派系的愿望
It's what all the other factions want,
既然无私派失败了
now that Abnegation failed.
不是 这只是他们告诉你的
No. That's just what they're telling you here...
- 这是真的  - 不是真的
- It's true. - It's not true.
不是
It's not.
他们都是骗子
There are liars here.
他们知道怎样操纵你的思想
There are people who know how to manipulate you.
你得明白这一点
You need to understand that.
Beatrice
Beatrice.
我想你该走了
I think you should go.
派系大于血缘 是吗
Faction before blood. Yeah?
我懂了
Got it.
你得跟我来一趟
I need you to come with me.
住手
Stop!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
请坐
Please, sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴你今天来了
I'm glad you came here today.
是吗
You are?
你对新派系满意吗
Are you happy with your new faction?
很满意
Yeah.
但你来见你哥了
But you came to see your brother.
我只是 想和他聊聊
I just... I just wanted to talk to him.
你见过你父母吗
Have you seen your parents?
没有
No.
很难放下吧
It's hard to let go.
派系大于血缘
Faction before blood.
这是个重要理念
It's an important ideal,
但有时很难实现
but sometimes difficult to fulfill.
它有违我们的天性
It goes against our fundamental human nature.
但这正是我们
But that's exactly the weakness
需要克服的弱点
we need to overcome.
你认为人的天性是弱点吗
You think that human nature is a weakness?
我觉得天性是我们的敌人
I think human nature is the enemy.
保守秘密 撒谎 偷窃 都是天性使然
It's human nature to keep secrets, lie, steal.
也正是我想根除的东西
And I wanna eradicate that.
这样才能维持稳定祥和的社会
That's how we'll maintain a stable, peaceful society.
你会帮我的 对吗
You would help me with that, wouldn't you?
我怎么帮得上你
How would I help you?
你知道无私派在破坏派系制度
You're aware that Abnegation is undermining the faction system
违反法律
and breaking laws
还窝藏分歧者吧
harboring Divergents?
我不知道
I didn't know that.
如果是真的 很高兴我选择了离开
But if that's true, then I'm glad that I left.
我想知道你是否可信
See, I need to know that I can count on you
可以协助执法
to enforce the law,
就算有亲人违法
even if it's been broken by someone close to you.
或者你在乎的人也一样
Someone you care about.
当然
Of course.
很好
Good.
我会派车送你回无畏派那儿
Then I'll have my car take you back to Dauntless.
来啊 把她拉过来
Come on! Get her over!
快点 快点
Come on, do it! Do it!
嘿
Hey!
你还好吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
快 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
给 穿上吧
Here, put this on.
谢谢
Thank you.
这儿很安全
You'll be safe here.
对不起
Sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
不敢相信Al居然
I can't believe Al...
你的排名在上升 他的在下滑
You're moving up through the ranks, and he's failing.
这让他怨恨自己 也怨恨你
It makes him hate himself and it makes him hate you.
他只是害怕了
He's just afraid.
每个人都很害怕
Everyone's afraid.
我知道 恐惧会让Al这种人变得不正常
I know, but fear does something strange to people like Al.
但你没有
But not you.
它没有让你退却 反而激发了你
Fear doesn't shut you down, it wakes you up.
我一直看在眼里
I've seen it.
你该躺下
You should lie down.
- 睡一觉吧  - 好的
- Get some sleep. - Yeah.
我去地上睡
I'll take the floor.
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
好多了
Better.
那就好
Good.
你昨天去哪了
Where'd you go yesterday?
去见我哥
To see my brother.
在这儿待着有点无聊 是吗
It's getting a little boring for you here, is it?
我哥说
My brother said that...
博学派计划把无私派赶下台
He thinks Erudite is planning to overthrow Abnegation.
你觉得他们会这么做吗
Do you think they could do that?
我觉得会 有这个可能性
Yeah, I do. I think it's possible.
这要看他们想做到哪一步
Depends how far they're willing to go.
我很担心我父母
I'm worried about my parents.
是啊
Yeah.
但你还有别的事要担心
But I think you got other things you need to worry about.
不是吗
Don't you?
是啊
Yeah.
我得走了
I should go.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
这是你的毛衣吗
Is that your sweater?
不是
No.
昨晚发生了什么
So what happened to you last night?
Tris 能跟你说两句吗
Tris, can I talk to you for a second?
听着 我只是想说声抱歉
Listen, I just wanted to say that I'm sorry.
我不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
求你了 你能原谅我吗
Please, can you ever forgive me?
如果你再靠近我 我会杀了你的
If you ever come close to me again, I will kill you.
Tris
Tris...
离我远点
You need to stay away from me!
你是个懦夫
You are a coward.
不敢相信他会这么做
I just can't believe he would do that.
那根本不像他
It's not like him at all.
那儿怎么了
What's that?
加把劲
Come on.
天哪
Oh, my God!
估计他是跳下去的
Guess he just jumped.
Tris
Tris.
Tris!
让我静一静
Leave me alone.
关于Al的事 很抱歉
I'm sorry about Al.
他死了是我的错
It's my fault that he's dead.
不 不是因为你 是他自己选择的
No, it's not because of you. He made his own choice.
他可能成为无派者
He would have been factionless.
也可能通不过最后的测试
He was not gonna pass that final test.
我也通不过
Neither am I.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
你知道原因的
You know why.
一旦其他人发现 我必死无疑
And as soon as all the others find out, they're gonna kill me.
我不会让那种事发生的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
关门
Shut the door.
你需要练习
You're gonna practice.
- 在我的恐惧幻象里吗  - 不
- In my fear landscape? - No.
在我的幻象里
In mine.
我们一起进去
We go in together.
你之前这么做过吗
Have you ever done this before?
没有
No, I haven't.
你确定想这么做吗
You sure you want to?
为什么不呢
Why wouldn't I?
我也不知道 你从没跟我说过你的事
I don't know. You haven't told me anything about yourself
现在却让我进入你的思想
and now you're just gonna let me inside of your head?
- 你害怕这个吗  - 你不怕吗
- Are you afraid of that? - You're not?
不怕
No.
恐高
Fear of heights.
意料之中
I'm not surprised.
这不是真的
It's not real.
- 可以直接跳下去  - 不行
- We could just jump. - No.
分歧者才会跳
Divergent would jump.
无畏派会进那栋楼
Dauntless would get to that building.
要想通过测试 不被调查
If you want to pass, if you want to avoid discovery,
你得按无畏派的想法去做
you have to do everything the way a Dauntless would do it.
你得找些工具 用些技巧活下来
You have to find some tool, some method to survive.
幽闭恐惧
Fear of confinement.
你得想办法阻止它靠拢 无畏派会怎么做
You have to find a way of stopping it. What would a Dauntless do?
很好
Good!
慢慢来
Take your time.
待在这缩小的盒子里 我还挺享受的
I'm just enjoying myself in this shrinking box.
作为无畏派的斗士
As a Dauntless soldier,
你必须服从命令 尽管有时你并不赞同
you have to follow orders you don't always agree with.
她是谁
Who is she?
她是个无辜的人
She's an innocent.
我得杀了她
I have to kill her.
但我做不到
But I can never do it.
除非我移开目光
Unless I look away.
我们怎么在无私派的地盘
Why are we in Abnegation?
最后的恐惧往往最可怕
Your last fear is your worst fear.
它藏在你心灵最深处
It lives in the deepest part of your mind.
Marcus有个儿子
Marcus had a son.
他叫什么
What was his name?
他叫Tobias
Tobias.
Tobias
Tobias...
我只是想让你更优秀
I'm just trying to help you to be better.
不
No!
四
Four?
四种恐惧吗
Four fears?
以前是四种 现在也是四种
Four then, four now.
我不断尝试 却从没摆脱过它们
I keep going in there, but I don't think you ever lose them.
能问你点事吗
Can I ask you something?
当然
Sure.
你的纹身是什么
What's your tattoo?
想看看吗
You wanna see it?
不可思议
It's amazing.
所有派系
The factions.
为什么都纹上了
Why do you have all of them?
我不想局限于一种类别
I don't want to be just one thing.
我做不到
I can't be.
我想成为既勇敢 无私
I want to be brave and I want to be selfless...
智慧 诚实又友好的人
Intelligent and honest and kind.
友好方面我还在努力
Although I'm still working on "Kind."
我不想进展这么快
I don't wanna go too fast.
没关系
It's okay.
反正我已经在你心里扎根了
I've already got my spot on the floor.
早上好
Morning.
嘿
Hey.
来 我想给你看些东西
Come on. I'm gonna show you something.
好
Okay.
看
Look.
- 博学派  - 没错
- Erudite. - Yeah.
他们每天早上都来
They're here every morning.
我暗中观察好几周了
I've been watching them for weeks.
他们来无畏派干什么
What are they doing at Dauntless?
装载物资 电脑
Loading in supplies. Computers.
还有这个
And these.
这是什么
What is it?
我觉得是某种认知递质液
I think it's some kind of cognitive transmitter.
像血清一样注射进体内
You inject it like a serum.
做什么用
Why?
让人更容易服从命令
It's supposed to make you more susceptible to suggestion,
但他们拥有的数量 足够建立一支军队了
but as many as they have, they could create an army.
请注意 新成员集合 进行最终测试
Attention, all initiates report for final testing.
新成员集合 进行最终测试
All initiates report for final testing.
你已经准备好了
You're ready.
你能行的
You can do this.
他们能在屏幕上看见你的幻象
They can see your hallucinations on the screen.
你要像无畏派那样战胜恐惧
So you get past your fears the way a Dauntless would,
但记得快一点
but do it quickly.
嗯 如果我太优秀会被杀
Right. If I'm too good, then they'll kill me,
而太慢会丧命
and if I'm too slow, then I'll die.
没错
Right.
加油
Good luck.
祝你好运 Tris
Good luck, Tris.
希望你能顺利通过
Hope you make it.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
哇哦 Four
Whoa. Four!
住手 Four
Stop! Four!
你不是无所畏惧吗
Aren't you Dauntless?
请告诉我你刚才没在看
Please tell me that you weren't watching that.
我要是说没看到你会好过点吗
Would you feel better if I said no?
表现不错
You did well.
现在
Now...
最终测试
One final test.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
什么
What?
如果你想成为无畏派
If you want to be Dauntless.
不
No.
动手
Do it.
你还好吗
You all right?
我觉得你做得很好
That looked good to me, okay?
来吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
祝贺你们
Congratulations,
成为新的无畏派
new members of Dauntless.
无畏派 无畏派 无畏派
Dauntless! Dauntless! Dauntless!
快点 排好队
Come on. Get in line.
好的 大家都排好队
All right, everybody, line up.
出什么事了
What's going on?
所有新的无畏派
All Dauntless initiates,
向你们的领队报到
report to your command leader.
好了 都听好了
All right, listen up!
在你们今晚离开之前 所有人都排成四队
Before you leave tonight, I want you all in four lines.
每个人都要植入跟踪装置
Everyone gets a tracking device.
不许提问 只是以防万一
Don't ask questions. It's just a precaution.
你看到Four了吗
Do you see Four?
没看见
No.
下一位
Next!
- 怎么回事  - 我的天啊
- What's going on? - Oh, my God.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你应该排在第一个 但是
You should be first in line, but...
我帮你省点事吧
I'll make it easy for you.
很疼是吧
Hurts like a bitch, huh?
现在你真正成为我们的一员了
Now you're really one of us.
嘿 怎么
Hey, what's...
派系大于血缘
Faction before blood.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
他们能察觉到我们的举动
They can see and hear us.
只是没法做出相应的反应
They just don't process it the same way.
命令通过递质传达
Commands come in through the transmitter.
怎么回事
What's goin' on?
我们要去干什么
What are we doin'?
分歧者
Divergent.
嘿 一切都好 没什么可担心的
Hey! Everything's fine. There's nothing to worry about.
动作快点
Hurry up! Move!
无私派领导者必须立刻表露身份
Abnegation leaders must identify themselves.
我们得赶紧找到我父母
We need to find my parents.
继续走 你家在哪里
Just keep moving. Where's your house?
我是在收集情报
We are looking for information.
所有房间都将被搜查
All houses will be searched.
不想受伤就不要做无谓的抵抗
Do not resist. You will not be hurt.
妈妈 爸爸
Mom? Dad?
他们能去哪儿
Where would they have gone?
我不知道
I don't know.
别这样 快停下
This can't happen here! Just stop it!
不要抵抗
Do not resist.
所有无私派都要接受审问
All Abnegation will be questioned.
传奇般的Four 还不是成了个白痴傀儡
The legendary Four... A mindless drone.
你曾是班里第一名 现在
You were first in your class. Now you're...
一无是处
Nothing.
怎么了
What?
他可能是
Think he might be...
只有一个办法查清楚
There's one way to find out.
- 说再见吧 混蛋  - 再见
- Say goodbye, asshole. - Goodbye.
动一下你就死定了
Move and you die!
呆瓜
The stiff?
两个呆瓜
Two stiffs.
两个快死的呆瓜
Two dead stiffs.
一个分歧者都不能放过
You can't let a single Divergent slip through.
- 这就是后果  - 她不会开枪的
- This is what happens. - She's not gonna shoot me.
你或许高估了我的本性
Think you might be overestimating my character.
快跑
Run!
- 你中枪了  - 对
- You were hit? - Yeah.
不许动
Right there! Don't move!
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
Tobias Eaton
Tobias Eaton.
还有你 Beatrice
And you, Beatrice.
我还以为你挺聪明的
I thought it was intellect I was sensing in you.
或许是你没自己想象的那么聪明
Maybe you're not as smart as you think you are.
你们为什么要袭击无辜百姓
Why are you attacking all these innocent people?
无辜百姓
Innocent people?
如果不消灭无私派 他们会毁掉整个派系制度
Abnegation, if left unchecked, will destroy the faction system.
对于你们来说也一样
Same can be said of both of you.
总得有人阻止你们 如果我们不阻止 和平就不复存在
Somebody has to stop you. If we don't, peace will be lost.
早已没有和平 是你一手毁掉的
It's already been lost. You destroyed it.
是人性毁掉的
Human nature destroyed it.
我们之中有远见的人
Those of us with the vision
有责任保护其他人
to see that are called upon to protect the rest.
我们会恢复和平 这次和平会永存
We will restore the peace. And this time, it will last.
要是你们错了呢
And what if you're wrong?
把他留下
Bring him with us.
她受伤了 测试结果会受影响
She's injured. Any results would be unclear.
- 你可以除掉她了  - 好的
- You can get rid of her. - All right.
趴下
Get down!
快走 老实点
Let's go. Come on!
后备保安队 向五级机动指挥部报告情况
Additional security teams, report to mobile command Level 5.
Beatrice
Beatrice!
- 妈妈  - Beatrice
- Mom? Mom! - Beatrice.
好了
Okay.
好了 我们赶紧跑
Okay, we gotta run!
你曾是无畏派
You were Dauntless.
今天终于派上用场了
Served me well today.
爸爸还好吗
Is Dad okay?
恩 他带了一队人去了Monroe那
Yeah. He led a group over to Monroe and State.
我们去那里和他碰面
We're gonna meet him there.
我们走
Let's go!
收到
Copy 1-9!
Will Will
Will! Will!
Will Will 住手 住手
Will! Will, stop! Stop!
住手
Stop!
我
I...
好了 快点 宝贝 我们得赶紧走
Okay. Come on, honey. We gotta go.
我杀了他 我杀了他 我杀了他
I killed him. I killed him. I killed him.
过来
Come here.
好了
Okay.
我们去找你爸爸
Let's go find your father.
- 掩护我  - 不
- Cover me. - No.
我去
I'll go.
发现目标 长官
Got it, sir!
别停下 快跑
Don't stop! Don't stop!
跑
Go!
- 你没事吧  - 恩 没事
- You okay? - Yeah, good. I'm good.
好了 我们走 安全了
Okay! Let's go! We're good.
妈妈
Mom?
妈妈 你怎么了
Mom... What is it?
嘿
Hey...
妈妈 妈妈 妈妈
Mom! Mom! Mom!
妈妈 不要
Mom! Mom, no!
妈 妈妈
Mom! Mom!
妈 妈 妈 醒醒
Mom? Mom! Mom, wake up!
妈妈
Mom!
天呐 妈妈
Oh, my God, Mom!
停下来 停
Stop! Stop!
我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom...
天呐
Oh, my God!
我爸爸在哪
Where's my father?
Beatrice
Beatrice?
你妈妈呢
Your mother?
她救了我
She saved me.
那就是死得其所
Then it wasn't in vain.
我们得离开这里
We need to leave here.
外面有士兵吗
Are there soldiers outside?
没有 很安全
No, it's clear.
我应该相信你的
I should have believed you.
我意识到以后马上就离开了
I left as soon as I realized.
为什么会是这样 我不明白
Why is this happening? I don't understand.
为什么无畏派要为博学派战斗
Why are Dauntless fighting for Erudite?
他们并不知道自己在干什么
They don't know what they're doing.
他们被操控了
They're under simulation.
我们得唤醒他们 我需要进入无畏派
We need to wake 'em up. I need to get into Dauntless.
那是个碉堡
That's a fortress.
进不去的
It's not gonna happen.
我能带大家进去
I can get us in there.
准备好
Get ready.
然后呢
What now?
你不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
下面有张网
There's a net at the bottom.
什么都别想 直接跳
Don't think, just jump.
你还好吗
Are you good?
没事吧
Good?
我们走
Let's go.
在这等着
Wait here.
靠墙站着
Against the wall.
Against the wall!
你为什么是清醒的
How are you awake?
因为我比你聪明
Because I'm smarter than you.
他们需要我
And they need me.
控制中心在哪
Where are they controlling it from?
我干嘛要告诉你 你是不会开枪的
Why would I tell you that? It's not like you're gonna shoot me.
为什么所有人都这么说
Why do people keep saying that?
控制中心在哪
Where are they controlling it from?
你不得不开枪打他吗
Did you really need to shoot him?
我们每浪费一分钟 都有一个无私派死去
Every minute we waste, another Abnegation dies
就会多一个无畏派变成杀手
and another Dauntless becomes a murderer.
Peter 我们走
Peter, let's go.
就是这儿 对吗
That's it, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
我看到Jeanine进去过
I've seen Jeanine go in there.
这就是她控制其他人的地方
That's where she's controlling it from.
就像你说的 时间可以浪费了
Like you said, there isn't a second to waste.
爸爸 不要
Dad, no!
爸爸
Dad...
不惜一切代价
Do whatever it takes...
嘿
Hey!
看好Caleb 我要进去了
Watch Caleb. I'm going in there.
嘿 嗨
Hey. Hi.
Four
Four...
Four Four 是我 你在模拟程序中
Four... Four, it's me. You're in a sim.
他听不见你
He can't hear you.
很神奇 不是吗
Amazing, isn't it?
我们能想到的一切人类属性
Everything we think of that makes up a person,
思维 感情 记忆
thoughts, emotions, history...
都被化学物质抹掉了
All wiped away by chemistry.
Four
Four.
他已经不在了
He's gone.
我们也变得更安全
And we're all safer for it.
更安全 怎么会更安全
Safer? How are we safer?
派系制度最伟大之处就是
The brilliance of the faction system
排除异己 完成派系的一致性
is that conformity to the faction removes the threat
消除任何拥有独立思维的人
of anyone exercising their independent will.
分歧者威胁了整个体系
Divergents threaten that system.
别误解我
Don't get me wrong.
你的反抗确实蕴含着一定的美感
There's a certain beauty in your resistance,
是你对分类的反抗
your defiance of categorization.
但是这种美感我们承担不起
But it's a beauty we can't afford.
Four 是我 是我
Four, it's me. It's me.
求你了 Four 看着我 看着我
Please, Four, look at me. Look at me.
Four 是我
Four! It's me!
Four 停下来
Four, stop!
别这样
Stop!
停
Stop...
Four 求你了
Four... Please...
没事 没事 我爱你 没事的
It's okay, it's okay. I love you. It's okay.
没关系
It's okay.
我爱你 没关系
I love you. It's okay.
Four 看着我 看着我
Four, look at me. Look at me.
是我 是我
It's me. It's me.
Tris
Tris...
去吧
Go.
快搞定
Finish it.
救命啊
Help!
嘿
Hey!
把它关掉
Shut it down.
不
No.
我不会再问你第二遍 快点
I am not gonna ask you again. Do it!
关掉
Shut it down!
我钦佩你愿为信仰舍生忘死
I admire you willing to die for what you believe...
但我也一样
But so am I.
你下不了手 是吗
You can't do it, can you?
或许你根本没有你想象的那么无所畏惧
Maybe you're not quite as Dauntless as you thought you were.
你说得对
You're right.
我没有
I'm not.
我是分歧者
I'm Divergent.
现在把它关掉 清除整个系统
Now shut it down and wipe the program.
模拟程序终止
Simulation abort.
系统全面关闭
System-wide shutdown.
不 不
No... No...
不
No!
别误解我
Don't get me wrong.
你的反抗确实蕴含着一定的美感
There's a certain beauty to your resistance.
Tris
Tris...
禁闭系统现在启动
Lockdown now in effect.
好了 我们走
All right, let's move!
我们得走了 就现在
We gotta go. Now.
Tobias
Tobias.
我们得赶紧离开
We need to keep moving.
好了 快走
All right, move!
儿子
Son!
我能行
I got it!
我知道
I know you do.
我父母今天都死了
My mom and dad died today.
他们都不在了
They're gone.
我知道
I know.
但他们都很爱你 Tris
But they loved you, Tris.
对他们来说 这是最好的表现方式
For them, there was no better way to show you.
现在我们什么都没有了
Now we have nothing.
没有家 没有派系
We have no home, no faction...
我甚至都不知道自己是谁
I don't even know who I am anymore.
我很清楚你是谁
I know exactly who you are.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
很确定
Yeah, I'm very sure.
过来
Come here.
我们现在是无派者
We're like the Factionless now.
必须将一切抛在脑后
We've left everything behind,
但是我们找到了自我 找到了彼此
but we found ourselves and each other.
也许明天我们还要继续战斗
Tomorrow we may have to fight again,
但现在 我们将乘着列车直到尽头
but, for now, we'll ride the train to the end of the line...
然后 跳出去
And then we'll jump.
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组